PERSONAL INFORMATION

Muhammad Masudur Rahman



- Uttara 10, Dhaka, Bangladesh
- +8801709036155
- madhnagar@gmail.com
- https://masud.gbytesoft.xyz/
- Skype masud.rahman762

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Frontend Developer professional with more than 4 years of experience in efficient and large-scale web-based systems development. I have moderate frontend development skills with an interest in DevOps/server administration. I love to write clean code and follow best practices. Seeking a position to become a reliable Frontend Developer where I will be able to learn and apply core Frontend engineering architectures, reliable system development principles.

Github: https://github.com/masud001

Stackoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/7111854/masudur-rahman

Gitlab: https://gitlab.com/Masudur

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/masud001/

WORK EXPERIENCE

2021 - Present

Frontend Developer

Riseup Labs (Dhaka, Bangladesh)

- Developing and Designing the web user interface.
- Client-side scripting and JavaScript Framework React.js, Vue.js,Svelte.js.
- Ensure Cross-browser compatibility, mobile-friendly pixel Perfect retina-ready user interface Design and Develop.
- Working with version control systems such as GitHub and GitLab.

2020 - Present

React Developer (Remote)

Oametrix (United Kingdom)

- Ensuring user experience determines design choices.
 - Worked with advanced web development technologies like React, MongoDB, ECMAScript 6, Typescript, JavaScript, Python, Bootstrap 4, CSS, HTML, JavaScript.
 - Validated customer interface requirements and assessed the impact of needs on available systems.
 - Developed custom Redux Form scripts for updating the Redux store using immutable and Redux Thunk.
 - Enforced Agile and Scrum development methodologies on interface projects to shorten development times.
- Took ownership of the app, used Jira tool for requirement gathering, GitHub, and GitLab as version control systems.

2018 - 2020

Frontend Web Developer(Remote)

Brqx Org (Madrid, España)

- Experience with technical support and Drupal infrastructure administration.
- Determining the structure and design of web pages.
- Ensuring user experience determines design choices.
- Developing new features to enhance the user experience.
- Ensuring web design is optimized for smartphones.
- Building reusable code for future use.
- Optimizing web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Utilizing a variety of markup languages to write web pages.

2015 – 2017 Junior Frontend Web Developer(Remote)

Brqx Org (Madrid, España)

- Experience with technical support and administration of the Drupal infrastructure.
- Experience with developing and designing Web sites in Drupal, WordPress.
- Experience with technical support and Drupal infrastructure administration.
- Strong experience with Javascript, HTML, and CSS.
- Knowledge of continuous integration, continuous deployment, and test-driven development practices.
- Demonstrated ability to research technical solutions independently.
- Conduct code reviews and peer mentorship.

2016 – Present Lead Front-end Developer, Co-Founder

QbyteSoft, (Dhaka, Bangladesh)

- Assisted in monitoring and reporting on website traffic and performance.
- Created HTML email templates and newsletters for email marketing campaigns.
- Developed website mock-ups for clients to ensure quality control and client satisfaction before the project development phase.
- Executed and monitored standards for user interfaces, page design, and graphics development.
- Designed complex interfaces to support third-party systems.
- Web page development from design to testing and up to production deployment.
- Ensured implementation of best SEO practices.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2014–Present Certificate of Responsive Website design and Development

Udemy Online Learning Program

- Certification Date: 2016-2017 (https://www.udemv.com/certificate/UC-TFJX2FCN)

2015–2019 Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering

International University of Business Agriculture & Technology

- Thesis: Open Courseware Management System

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Have mostly worked with Languages: JavaScript.

Frameworks/CMS: CodeIgniter, WordPress,Shopify. **Databases & Storage:** MySQL, MongoDB,Firebase.

Version Control: Git with Smart Git Flow; used with Bitbucket, Github, Gitlab. **Front End Development:** HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Vue.js,React, Svelte .js.

Others: Webpack, yarn,npm,Gulp, OAuth, JWT.

Code Testing Tools: Jest, Cypress.
Code Editors & IDE: Visual Studio Code.

SCRUM/Agile: Completed CSM Training and practicing SCRUM methodology at

work.

Have knowledge of **Languages:** Python, PHP, C++.

Frameworks/CMS: Django, OpenEdx, Drupal.

Databases & Storage: PostgresSQL.

Areas of improvement **Domain-driven development** practices.

Preparing for **Backend Development**. Learning **Angular.js**, **Amazon AWS**.

Foreign language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B2	C1	C1	C1	C1

English

Communication skills

- → Excellent communication skills gained through working with foreign clients, co-workers from different countries.
- → Good networking and presentation skills gained through attending and speaking in many international summits and conferences.

Organizational/managerial skills

- → Excellent leadership skills gained as a founder of a community-based coding education platform; responsible for organizing and speaking at workshops.
- → Managed a team of 6 developers and connected stakeholders.